Campaign Collection
Campaign Collection
1800-1972
5 linear ft.
Ribbons, campaign literature, posters, photographs, clippings, etc. relating to x years of American campaigns
2642884
Biographical History
The first U.S. presidential election took place in 1789. Technically there were twelve candidates but George Washington was the undisputed first choice; the other candidates were really competing to see who would be Vice-President, since at that time the recipient of the second-highest number of votes took that office. Since then there have been 55 presidential elections, hundreds of congressional and senate elections at the national and state level, and thousands of others for lower-level offices. All have involved campaigns with their accompanying paraphernalia: buttons, pins, brochures, booklets, stamps, ribbons, hats, posters, photographs, pamphlets, platform statements, scarves, figurines, bumper stickers, slogans, and more.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Campaign Collection consists of ribbons, campaign literature, posters, photographs, clippings, and more relating to nearly two hundred years of American political campaigns. Most are presidential campaigns but there are a few mayoral and others represented. Candidates represented include Abraham Lincoln, Thomas Dewey, Millard Fillmore, James Garfield, Grover Cleveland, Alf Landon, Adlai Stevenson, Richard Nixon, Ulysses S. Grant, William McKinley, William H. Taft, Herbert Hoover, Franklin Roosevelt, Wendell Wilkie, Martin Van Buren, Harry S. Truman, J. Strom Thurmond, and Harold Stassen. Parties represented include the Democratic and Republican but also the Socialist, States' Rights, Independent, Progressive, and Prohibition parties. There are also a few items from other major events such as the Panama Pacific International Exposition, a banquet for Secretary of the Navy Victor Metcalf, and party conventions.
also has several drawers of campaign memorabilia in the file cabinet along the West wall. These have not been inventoried. Please inquire for more information.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is in no particular order. The inventory is a box list only.
Related Material
has many collections relating to politics and government. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Popular culture; Democratic Party (U.S.); Prohibition Party (U.S.); Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Campaign literature.; Campaign paraphernalia.; Campaign insignia.; Political campaigns -- Souvenirs (Keepsakes); Political candidates -- Souvenirs (Keepsakes); Political parties -- United States -- Souvenirs (Keepsakes); Brochures.; Bumper stickers.; Buttons (information artifacts); Clippings (information artifacts); Invitations.; Songs (document genre); Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Campaign memorabilia
  - Commemorative coin with tassel, Horatio Seymour and Francis P. Blair for president and vice president, 1868 (Box 1)
  - Ribbons, Kingston Total Abstinence Society (Box 1)
  - Ribbons, Washington Association, 1844 (Box 1)
  - Ribbons, American Republican Celebration (Box 1)
  - Ribbons, Washington Monument (Box 1)
  - Ribbons, July 4, 1800 (Box 1)
  - Ribbons, Nov. 22, 1837 (Box 1)
  - "Election Medals of the Campaign of 1814" (Box 1)
  - Ribbons, Henry Clay, 1832 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia and ribbons, Andrew Jackson, 1832 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, William Henry Harrison, 1840 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Inaugural Ball, Tippecanoe, William Henry Harrison, 1841 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, Young Native American Association, 1844 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, American Republican Procession, 1844 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, Welcome Kossuth, 1850 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, Commemoration Anniversary, Birth and Death of Zachary Taylor, 1850 (Box 1)
  - "Medalets of the Presidential Campaign of 1852-1853" (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, Millard Fillmore/Fremont, 1856 (Box 1)
  - Writings, "Has the War Ruined our Country?", 1864 (Box 1)
  - Clipping, NY Herald, Assassination of President Lincoln, April 15, 1865 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, US Centennial, 1876 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Republican conventions and platform, 1876 (Box 1)
  - Photograph, Hayes, 1878 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Electors List, 1880 (Box 1)
  - Photograph, Lucretia R. Garfield, 1880 (Box 1)
  - Writing, "The Issue of Speech of Roscoe Conkling", September 17, 1880 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Inaugural Reception for James Garfield, 1881 (Box 1)
  - Photograph, Pres. and Mrs. Grover Cleveland, 1886 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Republican Campaign, NY state, September 10, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Song Book, Grover Cleveland and Thurmond, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Inaugural Ball Souvenir, March 4, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Cleveland and Stevenson Club, King Co., Proceedings, Nov. 11, 1892 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, "Play Money" ad for Cleveland Bank, 1892 (Box 1)
  - Writings, General Bidwell "Don't Throw Your Vote Away", 1892 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Inauguration Program, Cleveland, Stevenson, March 4, 1893 (Box 1)
  - Photograph, Mr. and Mrs. William Jennings Bryan, 1897 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Tobacco ad for Blackwell Bull Durham Tobacco, "US Grant" (Box 1)
  - Card, undated (Box 1)
  - Photograph, Abraham Lincoln (Box 1)
  - Photograph, William McKinley, 1843-1901 (Box 1)
  - Writing, Republican Campaign Book, 1903 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, 50th Anniversary Republican Party in Jackson, Michigan, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Prints, Four Generations of the Parker Family, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, "Buckwell Breakfast" Celebration, Theodore Roosevelt, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, Theodore Roosevelt, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Commemorative Program Banquet for Victor Metcalf, Secretary of Navy, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, William H. Taft Invitation, 1908-1910 (Box 1)
  - Tennessee Election Laws, 1911-1915 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Invitation, Panama Pacific International Expo., October 14, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Electoral Ticket for Martin Van Buren and Richard Jackson, undated (Box 1)
  - Signatures, undated (Box 1)
  - Our Presidents, 1916 (Box 1)
  - Poster, Memorial Service, Warren G. Harding, 1923 (Box 1)
  - "The Numismatist" vol. 37, Feb. 1924 (Box 1)
  - Writing, Music Score "March to the White House", 1924 (Box 1)
  - Writing, Calvin Coolidge, his first biography by R.M. Washburn, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon, J. McInerney, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Coolidge and Dawes, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Al Smith license plate, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Charles Curtis, Vice President, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Herbert Hoover, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Herbert Hoover, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Candidate information, Alf Landon, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, bumper sticker, Alf Landon/Frank Knox Candidate, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, play money, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Franklin Roosevelt, undated (Box 1)
  - Photograph, Governor Alf Landon for President, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Cook County Ill. Precinct Captain's weekly report, Republican Committee, October 19, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Look Magazine article on Wendell Wilkie, F. Roosevelt, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Literature, anti-Roosevelt, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Literature, minor parties, 1940s (Box 1)
  - Literature, Republican Party, 1940-1950 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Democratic Party, 1940-1950 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Republican Party, 1942-1948 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Republican National Convention, 1942-1948 (Box 1)
  - Election results, analysis of results of Republican Party, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Literature, George McKibbin, Republican Party Candidate for Mayor, Chicago, Illinois, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Dewey and Bricker, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Henry Black, Candidate, Presidential, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Socialist Party, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Literature, F. Roosevelt and H. Truman, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, Wendell Wilkie, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Writings, "He Trusted the People and they Remember Wendell Wilkie", 1945 (Box 1)
  - Literature, NY state, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Republican Party, 1946-1950 (Box 1)
  - Clipping, Report on Presidential Committee on Civil Rights, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, acceptance speech, Strom Thurmond and F. Wright, States Rights Candidates, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Taft-Hartley Law, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Socialist Party, 1948 (Box 1)
  - States Rights Party, Strom Thurmond and Fielding L. Wright, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Literature, senatorial race, Ken Keating NY (Box 1)
  - Literature, Robert A. Taft for President, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Literature, Harold Stassen, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Henry Wallace, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Committee for Constitutional Government (Box 2)
  - Literature, Dwight D. Eisenhower and Richard Nixon, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Taft, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Democratic National Convention, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Republican National Convention, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Taft, Dewey, Stassen (Box 2)
  - Literature, Democratic Party, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Thomas E. Dewey, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, D. MacArthur, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Harold Stassen, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Henry Wallace, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Thomas E. Dewey and Earl Warren, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, cartoons, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Thomas E. Dewey, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Taft campaign song, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Harold Stassen, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Photograph, H. Truman, Buffalo Courier Express, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Republican Convention, Candidate Harold Stassen, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Writings, Republican Platform, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Illinois primary official vote, April 13, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Writings, Socialist Party National Platform, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Inaugural Invitation, Truman, January 20, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Literature, National Liberal Federation of Canada, Bill Poupore, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Republican Party, 1940-1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Democratic Party (Box 2)
  - Literature, Onondaga County, New York (Box 2)
  - Literature, Senate and Congress, 1950s (Box 2)
  - Literature, Independent Party, Progressive Party, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Literature, state offices, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Cartoons (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Congressman Walter Riehlman Cookbook (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Democratic Party, undated (Box 2)
  - Writings, "How your Senator Representative Votes" AFL-CIO PAC, 1947-1956 (Box 2)
  - Writings, Readers Digest article "The Mistakes that Led to Korea", Nov. 1950 (Box 2)
  - Writings, "Why Foreign Aid" - facts about the Mutual Program Security, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Earl Warren Nominee for President, Democratic Convention, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Congress, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Senate, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, State Offices, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Adlai Stevenson, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Robert Taft, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, Backing Democratic and Adlai Stevenson, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Republican Convention Official Program, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Writing, Republican National Convention Roll, Chicago, Illinois, July 7, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Writing, Telephone Directory, Republican National Convention, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, Democrats, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, Republicans, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, Thomas Dewey, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, A. Harriman, undated (Box 2)
  - Literature, A. Stevenson, John Sparkman, Democratic Candidates, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Writings, "Guide to 1952 Presidential Convention" (Box 2)
  - Sample ballot, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Republican Party, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, A. Stevenson, John Sparkman, 1952 (Box 2)
  - 25th Republican National Convention, July 7, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Chicago Republican Platform, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Robert Taft, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, Robert Taft, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Eisenhower and Nixon, Presidential candidates, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Election Bulletin League of Women Voters, Erie County, New York, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Convention, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Socialist Platform, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Republican Campaign, Taft, Nixon, Eisenhower, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Democratic Campaign, Stevenson, Russell, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Literature, Everett M. Dirksen, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Photo, newspaper, magazine, T. Roosevelt (Box 3)
  - Literature, Independent Grocergram, Glen Taylor, John Dempey (Box 3)
  - Amendment to National Labor Act Prohibition Platform (Box 3)
  - Photograph, photo print (Box 3)
  - Literature, Estes Kefauver for President, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, A. Stevenson, Democratic Party, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Socialist party, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Democratic platform, 1952 (Box 3)
  - "The Key to Democratic Victory," Women's Division, Democratic National Committee, 1952 (Box 3)
  - The Book of Presidents, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Democratic Convention, candidates Robert Kerr, Hubert Humphrey, Richard Russell, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, T. Dewey, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Oscar Ewing, Nominee for Presidential Democratic Convention, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Stuart Hamblen, Dr. E.A. Holtwick, Prohibition Party, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Brien McMachon Democrat, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Michigan Republican State Central Committee, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Harriman, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Louisiana Republican Party, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Michigan Republican Party, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, polling information (Box 3)
  - Literature, Prohibition Party, 1944-1952 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Progressive Party, Vincent Hallinan, Charlotte Bass (Box 3)
  - Literature, Republican Party, undated (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Eisenhower/Nixon, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Eisenhower/Nixon, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
  - 82nd Congress Republican Accomplishments, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
  - 83rd Congress 1953-1954: An Appraisal and Republican Accomplishments (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Joyce Larkin, Republican, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Thomas Burke, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Excerpts from State of the Union, Dwight Eisenhower, Jan. 7, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Republican Party 100th Anniversary, Ripo, Wisc., 1954 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Republican Party 100th Anniversary, Jackson, Michigan Freedom Festival (Box 3)
  - Literature, A. Stevenson, Estes Kefauver, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Writing, T. Roosevelt, Centennial Committee, Republican Party, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Eisenhower, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Eisenhower and Nixon, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Eisenhower and Nixon, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Farmers for Roosevelt, undated (Box 3)
  - Literature, Kefauver, undated (Box 3)
  - Literature, Labor Party, 1944-1958 (Box 3)
  - Literature, 1948-1958 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Senatorial Election, 1940-1958 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Democratic National Committee, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Literature, Socialist Party, 1956-1958 (Box 3)
  - Illustrations, Presidents and Famous Americans, letters relating to collection, 1960-1962 (Box 3)
  - Ribbons, Columbian Total Abstinence Society (Box 3)
  - Ribbons, Patriotic Order of the Sons of America (Box 3)
  - Ribbons, Lafayette (Box 3)
  - Ribbons, George Washington, Centennial of his birth (Box 3)
  - Candidate information, Woodrow Wilson (Box 3)
  - Ribbons, Washington Temperance Benevolent Society (Box 3)
  - Sample ballots, national and state (Box 3)
  - Ribbons, William Henry Harrison (Box 3)
  - "Interesting Facts about the Presidents" (Box 3)
  - "Political Americana," incomplete run, 1960-1965 (Box 3)
  - "The Religion of Presidents" (Box 3)
  - Literature, Nixon, Henry Cabot Lodge, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Photograph, Truman (Box 3)
  - Writing, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Exhibition Catalogue "America Goes to the Polls", 1789-1960; highlights of Presidential Polls (Box 3)
  - Photograph, Kennedy inauguration, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Barry Goldwater, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, Senatorial and Congressional (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Clippings, Eisenhower/Nixon, Kennedy/Johnson (Box 3)
  - Writings, "Facts for Voters," League of Women Voters, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Republican New York state (Box 3)
  - Literature, Barry Goldwater/William Miller, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Literature, Lyndon Johnson/Hubert Humphrey, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Literature, Taft (Box 4)
  - Literature, Alben W. Barkley (Box 4)
  - Literature, Harriman (Box 4)
  - Literature, Goldwater/Miller, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Literature, Lyndon Johnson/Hubert Humphrey, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Literature, Goldwater/Miller, 1964; duplicate copies (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia, Nixon, 1968-1972 (Box 4)
  - Photograph, Nixon (Box 4)
  - Photograph, Stevenson (Box 4)
  - Photograph, Taft (Box 4)
  - Writings, "Biographical Sketch and Excerpt from his Writing and Address," T. Roosevelt" (Box 4)
  - Writings, Brochure, T. Roosevelt, Analostom Island Memorial Park, Washington (Box 4)
  - Writings, list of T. Roosevelt associations (Box 4)
  - Writings, Brochure, T. Roosevelt National Memorial Park, North Dakota (Box 4)
  - Writings, T. Roosevelt "Rooseveltiana" (Box 4)
  - Photograph, Nixon and Family (Box 4)
  - Literature, Anti-Stevenson, undated (Box 4)
  - Photograph, Eisenhower, undated (Box 4)
  - Literature, Michigan Republican Party, undated (Box 4)
  - Literature, Taft-Hartley Act (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia, Nixon/Lodge bumper sticker (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia, T. Roosevelt (Box 4)
  - Clipping, T. Roosevelt (Box 4)
  - Photograph, Rutherford B. Hayes, printed photo (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 4)
  - Poster, Eisenhower (Box 4)
  - Print and letter, James G. Blaine (Box 4)
  - Print, William McKinley (Box 4)
  - Ribbon, Abraham Lincoln after Emancipation Proclamation (Box 4)
  - Photograph, F. Roosevelt, February 13, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Photograph, Grover Cleveland (Box 5)
  - Photograph, McKinley (Box 5)
  - Photograph, Garfield (Box 5)
  - Photograph, Thomas Dewey celebration (Box 5)